Finding Aid for Church Women United in Chelsea records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Church Women United in Chelsea records 1961-1992
Church Women United in Chelsea
1.65 linear feet (in 2 boxes)
2014054 Aa 2
Records of Chelsea, Michigan chapter of Church Women United, an interdenominational church women's organization. Minutes of meetings, reports, memoranda, scrapbooks, and collected printed materials relating to activities and interests.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from Church Women United in Michigan (donor no. 6474 ) in April 2012
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Church Women United is a national volunteer Christian ecumenical women's movement initiated and carried out by women in the United States and Puerto Rico. It is a movement that brings together women of diverse races, cultures and traditions in closer Christian fellowship, prayer, advocacy, and action for peace with justice in the world.
The Chelsea, Mich. chapter was formed in 1961 by a group of women executive officers of four Protestant denominations --Congregational Christian, Evangelical and Reformed, Episcopalian, and Methodist-- and other interested women from these and other churches.
Materials include reports outlining chapter's annual activities and finances, Chelsea chapter constitution, Board and chapter meetings minutes, memoranda, scrapbooks, guest books and directories, and collected printed items produced by the National and Michigan Church Women Unites.
Subjects:
Church Women United in Chelsea.; Women--Michigan--Chelsea--Societies and clubs.; Women--Religious life--Michigan--Chelsea.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Church Women United in Chelsea Records
  - Annual reports, 1966-1981 (with gaps) (Box 1)
  - Constitution (Box 1)
  - Directories (Box 1)
  - Meetings minutes
    - 1961-1969 (Box 1)
      (bound volume)
    - 1970-April 1980 (Box 1)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - September 1980-May 1992 (Box 1)
  - Memoranda, 1979, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Printed material, collected (Box 1)
  - Guestbook, 1975-1991 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1981 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1982-1991 (Box 2)
Related collections
Bentley Historical Library holds records of the following Church Women United organizations:
Church Women United in Michigan, 1929-1993. Finding aid available online
Church Women United in Ann Arbor, 1941-2004. Finding aid available online